Coleman Buffa - Full Stack Web Developer

Coleman is a professional complex problem solver with extensive experience helping teams and clients achieve their goals. Naturally curious and driven to learn everyday he also is a skilled luthier and woodworker and brings craftsmanship sensibilities to technology.

SKILLS

Computer Science - Algorithms, Efficiency, Time Complexity, Big O, Data Structures

Browser Based Technologies - HTML/CSS, Javascript/JQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap and Foundation, Handlebars, Local Storage, Session Storage, Indexed DB

Databases - MySQL, MongoDB

Server Side Development - User Authentication, Progressive Web Applications (PWAs), MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

API Interaction - API, JSON, AJAX

EXPERIENCE

UC Berkeley Extension Full Stack Web Developer BootCamp — Student

December 2020 - March 2021

Lemur Music, Berkeley, CA - Owner-Operator and Double Bass Luthier

April 2018 - December 2020

• Retail sales. Double bass repair and setup services. Manage production of various items.

Amec Foster Wheeler, Oakland CA - Geologist

October 2014 - March 2018

• Orchestrate complex environmental field investigations (subcontracting, permitting, and field oversight). Manage project budget, ensure safety standards, conduct scientific studies, and assist in maintaining engineered remediation systems.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz - B.S. in Earth Science 2011

As a highly motivated student Coleman was awarded two teaching assistant positions normally reserved for graduate students, and participated in a research project with a faculty sponsor.